Another great tool that Flexbox allows you,
من الأدوات الرائعة الأخرى من «فليكس بوكس»
is there are several ways for you to dynamically order
وجود العديد من الطرق التي تمكنك من تغيير ترتيب العناصر
the items inside your parent container using Flexbox code.
داخل الحاوية الرئيسية باستخدام برمجة «فليكس بوكس».
The three ways that we're going to look at today are row reverse and column reverse.
تشمل الطرق الثلاثة التي سنتطرق إليها:عكس الصف وعكس العمود.
Here we see that keyword reverse which can be used on the Flex direction setting.
نلاحظ أن عكس(reverse) id الكلمة المفتاحية التي يمكن استعمالها لتحديد الاتجاه المرن
The second way is the specific order of the HTML code.
أما الطريقة الثانية فهي الترتيب الدقيق لبرمجة HTML.
You can actually move the lines of code that you want to create the order.
إذ يمكن نقل سطور البرمجة بحسب الترتيب الذي ترغب به
The third is the order CSS property.
أما الثالثة فباستخدام خاصية order في CSS
The order CSS property is specifically for Flex items.
فهي مخصصة لعناصر «فليكس».
That is HTML elements that are inside of another HTML element that has the display Flex.
وهذا يعني عناصر HTML الموجودة داخل عنصر HTML آخر يتسم بخاصية عرض فليكس.
That's the Flex container,
وهذه هي الحاوية المرنة،
inside it are the flex items.
وبداخلها العناصر المرنة.
Flex items have a CSS property called
تتمتع العناصر المرنة بخاصية CSS
order that can set the order that they appear in your browser.
تُسمّى رتبة order، والتي يمكنها تحديد الترتيب الذي تظهر به في المتصفح.
Let's take a quick look at how these three different ones might happen.
لنلق نظرة سريعة علي كيفية عمل تلك الخيارات الثلاثة